《女子监狱》
第二季第十二集
这是无心之过  她是想帮忙的
It was an honest mistake. She was trying to help.
再多帮点忙  我就死了
A little more help and I'll be dead.
她讨厌戴眼镜  说显得鼻子大
She hates wearing her glasses. Says it makes her nose look big.
你想谋杀别人的话  视力是基本要求
You want to assassinate someone, vision is a basic requirement.
第一步  选择要杀的人
It's like step one, pick a person to kill.
第二步  杀掉那个人
Step two, kill that person.
她在禁闭室撑不到一个月
She won't last a month in the SHU.
这简直糟透了  姑娘们
This is a royal fuck-up, girls.
维会知道她是目标
Vee is going to know that she is the target.
整个家族都有危险
The whole family is in danger.
除非  我们利用这一点
Unless... we use it to our advantage.
她不知道那是搞错了
She doesn't know it was a mistake.
我们告诉她  那是鸣枪警告  别惹红妈
We tell her it's a warning shot. Don't fuck with Red.
不然一个79岁的老太就会捅你从没见过的人
Or a 79-year-old woman will shank someone you never met.
你就是这么可怕
That's how scary you are.
捅一个陌生人的肾脏  就为了警告别人
Stab a stranger in the kidney just to send a message.
如果我是维  我会仔细考虑要不要惹毛你
If I was this Vee person, I'd think twice about pissing you off.
塔斯利兹会希望如此
It's what Taslitz would want.
塔斯利兹把我们卷入了这个局面
Taslitz got us into this situation.
我们不能一错再错了
We're not doubling down on that nonsense.
我们得平静地解释发生的事
We need to explain what happened... peacefully.
谈判
A parley.
谈判  我们是海盗吗
Parley? What are we, pirates?
我们中的确有人有章鱼纹身
Well, one of us does have an octopus tattoo.
往窗户上贴胶布不是个好主意
Taping windows is not a good idea.
应急手册里有写到
It's in the emergency manual.
坏消息  飓风旺达
Bad news, Hurricane Wanda.
你被降级成了热带风暴
You've been downgraded to a tropical storm.
搞笑
Hilarious.
但是气象员说你范围更广了
The weatherman said you're getting wider, though.
你落地时能压平几棵树
You could flatten a few trees when your ass hits land.
好啦  史蒂夫・哈维  我们明白
Okay, Steve Harvey, we get it.
上次四号房  入口和药房里
Last time we had leaks in room four
都有漏水
and in intake and in the pharmacy.
他们夏天补了补
They did some patchwork over the summer,
但我对现在的情况并不乐观
but I am not optimistic about what's happening up there.
这地方需要新屋顶
This place needs a new roof.
菲格在忙这事了  别担心
Yeah, Fig is all over that. Don't worry.
她还要给我们建一家意式咖啡吧和游泳池
She's also getting us an espresso bar and a swimming pool.
看来你没吸取教训啊
So much for learning your lesson, huh?
什么教训
What lesson is that?
我不知道  和犯罪分子来往
I don't know, associating with the criminal element.
姑娘  我就是犯罪分子
Girl, I am the criminal element,
我记得你也是
and so are you, last time I checked.
你明白我的意思
You know what I mean.
别又说起这事
Man, don't start this again.
她害你进了禁闭室
Yo, she got you thrown in the SHU.
那不是她
That wasn't her.
是这地方像以前一样惩罚我
That was this place coming down on me like it's done before,
它还会再惩罚的
and it'll do it again.
总有事情会让你倒霉  知道吗
Something's gonna fuck you, you know?
体制  男人  维
The system, the man, Vee.
无能为力
Can't do nothin' about it.
至少维给你提10%的成
At least Vee gives you back 10%.
她夺走了我朋友
She took my friend.
你要一直跟她斗吗
And you gonna fight her forever?
别把事情搞得那么艰难
Stop making things so hard for yourself.
你没事吧  查普曼
You all right, Chapman?
没事
Yeah. Yeah.
跟你律师谈过了吗
Get to talk to your lawyer?
我跟他的搭档谈过了  他说...
I talked to one of his partners. He said that there's, um...
他说他们无能为力
he said that there's nothing that they can do.
他说囚犯经常被转狱
He said prisoners get transferred all the time.
去年来了三十个彭萨科拉监狱的姑娘
Yeah, we got, like, 30 girls up from Pensacola last year
当时那边闹肺结核
when they had that tuberculosis scare.
这不是那样
This isn't that.
这是菲格故意整我
This is Fig fucking me personally.
从愚蠢的广播剧开始  她就很恨我
She's hated me ever since that stupid radio show.
但你有关系
But you, you got connections.
你可以抵抗  你有休假
Now, you can fight this. You got furlough.
我有休假  现在我倒霉了
I got furlough, and it's biting me in the ass.
海利说他无能为力
Healy said that there's nothing he can do.
他不能再要特权了
He can't ask for any more special favors
因为看起来会不合适
because it would look inappropriate.
她把我和十来个人一起安排上了那个名单
She buried me on that list with, like, a dozen other people.
卢茨刚生了孩子
Ruiz has a new baby.
我会想你的  因为你曾是个正直的人
Well, I'm gonna miss you... 'cause you were a decent person.
你知道最糟糕的部分是什么吗
And do you know what the worst part of it is?
告诉我的家人  意识到
Telling my family and realizing
他们其实有些解脱
that they actually sounded kind of relieved,
好像他们不用
like they weren't gonna
花几个小时来监狱探视我
have to spend hours coming to visit me anymore,
好像他们终于拿回了周末
like they finally got their weekends back.
你该听听我妈妈说的话
I mean, you should've heard my mother.
她听起来真的很高兴
She sounded practically cheerful.
你只用服刑八个月
"Well... you only have eight months.
又不是一辈子
It's not like that's forever."
八个月就是一辈子
Eight months is forever.
好像你服刑的时间越短  过得就慢
It's like the less time you got, the slower it goes.
好了  我得走了
All right, I got to go.
莫里洛
Hey, Morello?
我来这里时  你是第一个
You know, you were the first person
对我友好的人
that was nice to me when I got here.
我当时真的很害怕
I was really scared.
你让我觉得会没事的
You made me feel like it was gonna be okay.
我会记住你这句话  心情不好时安慰自己
Well, I am gonna remember that you said that... for my bad days.
那是什么
What's that supposed to be?
是黑旗  谈判的国际象征
It's a black flag. International symbol for parley.
我们是海盗吗
And what are we, pirates?
我不跟你斗嘴  我是使者
I don't banter. I'm an envoy.
工作后去温室
The greenhouse. After work.
我要两份鸡汤面和新孢霉素
I'll take two chicken noodles and a Neosporin.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
-袜子不错  -谢谢
- Nice socks. - Thanks.
我想要提醒你
I'd like to alert you
一些感觉有差错的项目
to a couple of line items that feel a little wonky.
好吧
Okay.
比如说
For instance...
这里拔款了
we've got 80 grand here
八万块卫生间修理费给菲茨核心
allocated to FitzCORE for the bathroom repair,
但这笔款项应该是包含在之前的未指明
but I thought that was included in the fee we paid earlier
管道修理服务费用之中了
for unspecified plumbing services.
这项维修要大得多
This is a much more extensive job.
好吧  我知道
Right, I get that,
但我感觉有些重叠
but I feel like there's some overlap happening.
你做得很好  霍夫曼
You're doing great work, Hoffman.
谢谢
Thanks.
我觉得我们应该仔细研究
So, I think we should dig into this.
我丈夫今晚要举办一场募捐会
Listen, my husband is having a fundraiser tonight.
你作为我的客人出席吧  喝几杯鸡尾酒
Why don't you come as my guest? Have a couple cocktails.
妻子会喜欢的
The wife'll love it.
橄榄球巨星提克・巴贝尔好像也会去呢
I'm pretty sure Tiki Barber is gonna be there.
你怎么样
How's it going?
什么  我吗
What, me?
我挺好的  谢谢你问起
I'm doing okay. Thanks for asking.
其实你没法一直无视我
You know, it's actually not possible for you to ignore me forever.
他动了
He moved.
抱歉  我没听懂
I'm sorry, I'm not following.
宝宝  他动了
The baby. He moved.
什么时候  现在吗
When? Like now? Now?
今早  还有午饭后
This morning and again after lunch.
他真的在我肚子里
He's really in there.
我能不能...
Can I...
从外面还摸不出来  他太小了
Can't feel nothin' on the outside. He's too small.
等等  你叫婴儿"他"
Wait, you're calling it a "He."
我的右乳比左乳大
My right boob is larger than the other one.
歌洛丽娅说这表示是个男孩
Gloria says that means he's a boy,
而且我一直想吃咸的
and... I also keep craving salty stuff.
我一直都想要个男孩
I... You know, I always wanted a boy, like...
我就想象是个男孩
I mean, when I pictured it.
你觉得弗兰克这个名字
How do you feel about, um... Frank...
怎么样
as a name?
弗兰克  像热狗一样吗
Frank? Like a hot dog?
当我没说
Ah, never mind. It's...
也可能是女孩
It could be a girl, I guess.
是啊
Yeah.
我想是
Yeah, I guess.
该死
Oh, shit.
我好像记得你
I seem to recall you
说过她不会是个麻烦
saying that she wasn't going to be a problem.
你怎么知道是她啊
How do you know it was even her?
孩子会做孩子气的事
A child does childish things.
那个小蠢货让我赔大发了
That little broomstick just cost me serious money.
谁会付我钱  你吗
Who's gonna pay me back? You?
我跟这事没关系
Look, I got no part in this.
但你担了责任
But you took responsibility.
如果不是因为你  你觉得她会来搞破坏吗
You think she'd be in here trashing my shit if it wasn't for you?
你要怎么处理她
What are you gonna do to her?
我是个女商人  我要
I'm a businesswoman. I'm gonna do...
不惜一切代价消除风险
whatever it takes to neutralize the risk.
别发疯  维
Don't get crazy, Vee.
她可以出意外  这是一个选择
She could have an accident. That's one option.
接下来会怎么样
What's gonna happen then?
这地方会被封锁  狱警扔了一切
The whole place goes on lockdown, the COs tossin' everything.
这对生意不利
That's bad for business.
第二个选择是什么
So, what's option two?
消除她反抗我的动机  那就是你
Take away her incentive to fight me, which is you.
我不能再留着你了
I can't have you around here anymore.
但我是你的人
But I'm your girl.
我从第一天开始就对你忠心耿耿  随你问谁
I've been loyal to you from day one. Ask anyone.
我知道
I know that.
你朋友的这码子事
You see, this whole thing with your friend,
给我惹了很大麻烦  吸引了大家的注意
it is bringing me down, it is attracting attention,
我不能再这样下去了
and I can't have it anymore.
我会和她谈谈  我让她离远点儿
I'll talk to her. I'll tell her to stay away from...
瞧瞧这一团糟
Look at this mess. Look at this mess.
她就是想让大家看见
She left this for anyone to see.
如果狱警比我先进来
Now, what would've happened
会发生什么事啊
if a CO had come in here before me, huh?
她宁愿让你被关进禁闭室
She would rather have you go to the fucking SHU
也不愿意看你为我工作
than see you working for me.
抱歉  美味
I'm sorry, Taystee.
你说过你会保护我
You said you would protect me.
你说过我们会同舟共济
You said it was me and you together.
我们还会抬头不见低头见的
I'm sure we'll see each other around.
谁想要香辣鸡翅
Yo, who wants hot wings?
你为什么吃那垃圾食品
Oh, why do you eat that shit?
你知道那是抛售垃圾鸡肉的骗局吧
You know it's a scam to sell off the trash of the chicken?
可口的垃圾食品
Delicious trash.
我们以前会切掉鸡翅  然后扔了
We used to cut the wings off and throw 'em away.
知道吗
Did you know that?
然后有人想到如果把鸡翅沾满酱汁
Then somebody figured out if you smother 'em in sauce,
你就可以说服人们认为鸡翅很好吃
you could talk people into thinking that they were good.
你有没有注意到
You ever notice...
姑娘  你有没有注意到
Girl, you ever notice
他们从来不在别的鸡肉部分上放水牛酱
that they don't ever put buffalo sauce on no other chicken parts?
有人起床气不小啊
Somebody got up on the wrong side of the bed.
关掉侠盗飞车游戏过来  RJ
Yo, hang up the GTA and get in here. RJ!
我还以为你会买泰国菜
I thought you were gonna get Thai, you know,
我喜欢的咖喱面条
that curry soup with the noodles I like.
我们谈过了
We had this conversation.
你说你不信任
You said that you didn't trust a man
穿着人字拖做菜的厨师
who wore flip-flops while he cooks.
我想我是累了  我最近都没睡觉
I'm tired, I guess. I haven't been sleeping lately.
我告诉过你是披萨
I told you it was pizza, man.
你担心什么事吗
You worried about somethin'?
我卖海洛因  总是在担心
I sell smack. I'm always worried.
而且我的床垫太热了
Besides, my mattress is too hot.
你确定你没生病吗
You sure you ain't sick?
不  我才没生病  别摸我额头  我从不会生病
No, I'm not sick. Get outta here. I never get sick.
你没生病  维  你就是老了
You ain't sick, Vee. You just old.
我有个姑妈  总是在大叫大嚷  出汗
I had an aunt who was always yelling and sweating.
什么也记不起来了
Couldn't remember a damn thing.
原来是更年期到了
Turned out, it was the change.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我还没到更年期的年纪呢
I'm too young for that shit.
我还以为我有更多时间
I thought I had more time.
放松点
Hey, take it easy, now.
我都50岁了
Oh, I am 50 years old.
我这辈子干了些啥啊
What the fuck have I done with my life?
我该先租后买的  我该给自己找个男人
I should've rent to own. I should've got me a man!
你有我们啊
Well, you got us.
不如你先别抓狂
How about you put off losing your mind
先好好睡一觉
until you get a good night's sleep,
然后看看那时感觉如何
and then you see how you feel then?
我们都知道特兰斯
Okay, we all know Trance
经常说一些蠢话
says the first dumb thing that come to his mind.
擦  我都不信你50了
Shit, I don't even believe you 50.
你还是和我第一天遇见你一样美
You're still as fine as the first day I met you.
你真会瞎编
Boy, you so full of shit.
你是这房子里最会瞎编的人
You always the smoothest bullshitter in this house.
我说真的  维
I'm serious, Vee.
如果你不是像我妈一样
If you wasn't practically my mom,
我都不知道我会对你做出啥事
I don't know what might happen.
孩子  你快走开啦
Boy, you better get outta here.
你得一直跟她说话
You have to talk to her, like, all the time.
有很多研究表明  如果...
There's all these studies that say that if...
如果你不和宝宝说话
if you don't talk to the baby,
他们五岁时就会反应迟钝
they end up, like, fucked by the time they're five.
跟她说话  对她唱歌
Talk to her. Sing to her.
你得向我保证  好吗
You got to promise me, okay?
我去弗吉尼亚后  你要跟她念书
You'll read to her while I'm in Virginia.
我知道你不喜欢说话
All right, I know you don't like to talk,
但你得为了她说
but you gotta do it for her.
你听到了吗  小姑娘
Oh, you hear me, baby girl? Huh?
我在跟你说话呢  对啊  我在跟你说话呢
I'm talking to you. That's right, I'm talking to you.
你捏爸爸的脸  逼他说话
You grab Daddy's face and you make him say shit
这样你就不会和我一个下场了
so that you don't end up like me.
这是新体位吗
Oh, this something new?
要抬起臀部  不让精液流出来
You're supposed to keep your hips up. Keeps the sperm in.
你该穿衣准备了
You should start getting ready.
霍夫曼盯上我们了
Hoffman's on to us.
没盯上  但是起疑心了
Not on to us, but suspicious.
没有啦  在他那边我们没问题的  别犯错误
Nah, we're bulletproof on his end. Just don't make any mistakes.
我不想再这样了
I don't wanna do this anymore.
一开始很好玩
It was fun at first,
但现在我睡不着觉了
but now I'm not sleeping.
如果我被抓住了  你能想象吗
If I got caught, can you imagine?
天啊  宝贝  你现在害怕了吗
Jesus, babe, you're getting cold feet now?
如果你想赢  就得使阴招
You know, you gotta play dirty if you wanna win.
罗利进了办公室
Rowley gets in office,
就带领整个州自取灭亡
he drives the whole state off a cliff.
我明白
I get it.
这可是我的事业
This is my career we're talking about.
我的事业呢
And my career?
你知道我完全支持你  宝贝  各种方面都是
Look, you know I totally support you, babe, in every way...
但你是监狱里的副典狱长
but you're assistant warden in a prison.
这可是参议院  想想这会打开多少扇机会之门吧
This is the senate. Think of the doors it will open.
也许你会怀孕  对吧  谁知道呢
And maybe you'll get pregnant, right? Who knows?
我遵守了我的承诺
I held up my end of the deal.
你也要遵守
Now you hold up yours.
搞毛啊
What the hell?
想想吧  维
Think about it, Vee.
你真觉得我会做这么愚蠢的事吗
Do you really think I'd do something so stupid?
不  你不是愚蠢  只是可悲
No, you're not stupid. Just pathetic.
让一个老蠢货来做你不敢做的事
Just sent an old fool to do a job that you're afraid to do.
那个老蠢货做了她该做的事
That old fool did exactly what she was supposed to.
警告你
Send a warning.
敢惹我  我就报复
Fuck with me, I fuck back.
真的吗  因为你知道我收到的是什么消息吗
Really? 'Cause you know what the message that I got was?
你想要战争
You want a war.
不过你搞砸了第一枪
Except you bungled the first shot.
如果她想杀了你  你就死定了
If she wanted to kill you, you'd be dead.
你想干架吗
Do you... do you wanna go?
你知道悲哀的部分是什么吗
You know the sad part is,
我本想看在旧日情分上和你们分享
I was actually gonna share this with you for old times' sake.
但现在我受伤了
But now my feelings are hurt,
我就直接拿下了
so I'm just gonna take it.
好吧  希望你好好享受
Oh, well... I hope you enjoy it.
当然  如果你的人能找到另一头
If your people can find the other end, of course.
在森林里  荒无人烟的地方
In the woods, in the middle of nowhere.
你儿子怎么样
How's your son?
尤里  对吧
Yuri, right?
你能想象在利奇菲尔德两小时车程的范围内
Can you guess how many Yuri Reznikovs there are
有多少有尤里・泽尼科夫吗
in a two-hour driving radius of Litchfield?
来猜猜吧
Come on, guess.
你在吓唬人
You're full of shit.
就一个
There's only one.
肯伍德路2364号  还是2346号  我不记得了
2364 Kenwood Road, or is it 2346? I don't remember.
但我的手下告诉我那地方很不错
But my boys tell me it's very nice.
有花房  白色的装饰
Green house, white trim.
你敢碰我儿子  我就找你麻烦  血债血偿
You touch my son, I touch you. Every bruise, every mark the same.
你是要自己来跟我斗  红妈
You gonna fight me yourself, Red,
还是你要派遣一队矮子老太婆军队
or are you gonna send your little army of midgets,
来帮你跟我斗
crones to do it for you, huh?
诺尔玛  你最好让你朋友清醒点
Norma, you might wanna talk some sense into your friend here.
提醒她  她上次惹我的时候
Remind her of the last time that she fucked with me.
肋骨断裂
Broken ribs.
肺部刺破
Punctured lung.
你很骄傲  对吗  我们曾是朋友
You're proud of that, are you? We were friends.
我们才不是朋友
We were never friends.
你会后悔的
You'll regret that.
这是什么  茶话会吗  你们在这里干什么
What is this? A tea party? What are you even doing out here?
我们听到了警报
We heard the alarm.
这不是趴在地上的警报
It's not the lie-down-on-the-ground alarm,
而是天气警报
it's the weather-related-emergency alarm.
快走  回大楼里
Let's go. Get back to the building.
提醒我给你们都记过  走吧
And remind me to give you all shots. Let's go.
你妻子怎么样了
How's your wife?
她为孩子的事很紧张
Eh, she's stressed about the kid.
学校想让他留级  她觉得是针对她
School wants to hold him back. She takes that shit personal.
也许你该带她去别的地方  比如弗洛里达州
Yeah, well, maybe you should take her someplace, you know? Florida.
谁会照看我的伙伴  维
And who'd look out for my pal, Vee?
提醒她行动  围捕她的竞争对手
Tip her off to the action, round up her competition.
你的奉献真是感人
Your dedication is heartwarming.
我们很亲近了  对吗  除非没钱了
We're as close as can be, right? Till the money runs out.
顺便说一句
Oh, by the way,
我们在桥对面抓住了几个供货的
we busted a couple of supply guys across the bridge.
他们引进了印度的便宜货
They're bringing in this cheap shit from India.
端掉了整个窝  账簿  现金  一切东西
Took down the whole setup, books, cash, everything.
纽约警察真厉害
New York's Finest.
送货单上有你手下RJ
Your boy RJ was on their drop list.
地址一样  我查过了
Same address. I checked.
要问我  他要独立门户了
You ask me, he's going into business for himself.
大家继续走  慢点儿  大家都别弄湿了
Keep it moving, everyone. Nice and calm, we all stay dry.
雨水怎么会从马桶里冒出来啊
Hey, man, how is rain coming out the toilet?
你能给我解释吗
Can you explain me that?
不是雨水  而是湖水
It's not rain. It's the lake.
下水管是开通的  湖水泛滥
The sewer pipes are open, the lake overflows,
地下水就从管道里冒出来了
ground water comes up through all the pipes.
如果到了游泳的地步  我要拯救自己
If it come down to swimming, I'm gonna save myself.
我会站在一个贱人头上
I will stand on a bitch's head.
ACF宿舍  去餐厅报道
Dorm A, C and F, report to the cafeteria.
湿纸巾  我要拿这个做什么  吃了它吗
Wet-nap? What the fuck am I supposed to do with this, eat it?
也许比这玩意儿好吃
Probably tastes better than this.
奶油胡桃  而且是两年前的
Butter pecan, and it's from, like, two years ago.
是别人捐的
We get donations.
我们真是烦死你了  旺达
You're killing us, Wanda.
快  我们过去  你带了扑克吗
Come on, we'll go over there. You bring your cards?
今晚可能很漫长  有什么消遣的玩意儿吗
Could be a long night. Got anything to help me get through it?
离我远点  吊桶头  老娘没心情
Get away from me, kibble head. I am not in the mood.
我很肯定这是不安全的工作环境
Pretty sure that this qualifies as unsafe working conditions.
是啊  我肯定职业安全与健康管理局会来管的
Oh, yeah, I'm sure OSHA's gonna be all over it.
我对发电机一无所知
I don't know anything about generators.
发电机在屋顶上
The generator's on the roof.
我们得让泵运作起来  才能把燃料输送上去
We have to get the pumps working so they'll push fuel up there.
我也对泵一无所知
Also, I don't know anything about pumps.
他都说了
Hey, that's what he said.
拜托  我淹死或者电死之前
Come on, I can't make one stupid joke
都不能开个玩笑吗
before I die from drowning and/or electrocution?
-有东西漂来  -呕
- Incoming. - Ugh!
至少它死了
At least it's dead.
猜想他的兄弟们去干燥的楼上了
Think of his brothers heading upstairs to get dry.
你去看水槽  你去修泵
Okay, so tanks, pumps.
开始吧
Let's get going.
怎么没人告诉过我这些东西在下面
Man, how come nobody told me these things were down here?
我本可能囤积一个监狱烈酒市场的
I could've been cornering the prison-hooch market.
瞧瞧  这里还有嵌入墙里的水龙头呢
Look at this. They got taps built in and everything.
卢斯奇克  这里面什么也没有
Uh, Luschek? There's nothing in here.
搞毛啊
What the fuck?
都是空的吗
Both empty?
又是菲格  我说得对吗
Fig again. Am I right?
现在怎么办
Now what?
玩3P吗
Threesome?
讽刺之处在于傅科对权利结构的分析
So, the irony is that Foucault's analysis of power structures
最后成了反对
ends up being an argument
社会不平等体制的论据
against the institutions of social inequality.
我们经常在更衣室聊这个
I mean, we talk about this all the time in the locker room.
我不知道这为什么如此艰难
I don't know why this is so difficult.
然后杰森说  让我跟她谈谈  可不是嘛
So, then Jason says, "Let me talk to her." I know, right?
但我说不动他  所以我就给他接通
But he will not be swayed, so I put him on,
他坐在那里  跟她打了20分钟电话
and he sits there on the phone with her for 20 minutes.
我数过了  听着她扯那些
I counted. Just listens to her whole story
建筑执照还有蛇的事
about the building permits and the whole thing with the snakes,
我不知道他怎么做到的  但我对天发誓
and I do not know how he does it, but I swear to God,
他俩聊完后  她给他开了一张30美金的支票
at the end of that conversation, she writes him a check for $30.
这时我就知道了  这男人属于奥尔巴尼
And that's when I knew, this man belongs in Albany.
抱歉  我得跟她单独谈谈
Sorry, I need her for a minute.
抱歉  失陪一下  见到你们真好
Oh, I'm so sorry. Excuse me. It's good to see you.
谢谢你  天啊  如果我得再说一次那故事
Thank you. God, if I have to tell that story one more time...
又是乔・卡普托  这是第六通电话了
Joe Caputo again. This makes call number six.
简直跟带孩子一样
It's like having children.
我发誓  老娘就不能出来玩一晚上吗
I swear, can't Mama have one night out?
我猜我得给他回电话
I guess I should call him back.
菲茨核心的人刚到
FitzCORE just got here.
很好  我们需要他来付钱
Oh. Good, we need this guy to pony up.
鲍勃  真高兴你来了
Bob, so glad you made it.
兰迪  米歇尔  真抱歉下雨了
Randy, Michelle, I'm so sorry about the rain.
我很失望  娜塔莉
I'm disappointed, Natalie.
我还肯定你会想出办法来
I thought for sure you'd figure out
让坏天气推迟到今晚后出现呢
how to put the weather off until after tonight.
我现在就可以做到  但那需要你额外付钱
I could do it right now, but it'd cost you extra.
我不是在抱怨暴风  相信我
I'm not complaining about the storm. Trust me.
这就像是天上掉钱
It's like money falling from the sky.
我想你的监狱
I'm guessing that prison of yours
需要昂贵的修补吧
is gonna need some very expensive repairs.
我猜你说得对
I am guessing you're right.
-虾球要吗  -好
- Lobster slider? - Yes, please.
这边
This way.
这里
Here.
我们之间隔着围栏  但能看到对方
We keep the fence between us, but we can all see each other.
不会有突袭
No surprises.
你觉得她今晚就会行动吗
You think she's gonna jump you tonight,
当着五个狱警和两百个目击证人的面
in front of five COs and 200 witnesses?
我们碰上的可不是正常人
This is not a sane person we are dealing with.
天啊  我的心灵固然坚定
Oh, man. I mean, the spirit is willing and everything like that,
但是涉及到体重级别  我们问题就大了
but we got a serious problem in terms of weight class,
明白我的意思吗
you know what I'm saying?
我们没那肌肉  所以我们得聪明点
We don't have the muscle, so we've got to be smarter.
太棒了  我们下战书跟他们玩数独游戏
Great, we'll challenge them to a sudoku contest.
注意你的语气  吉纳
Watch your tone, Gina.
整晚都要有人监视她
I want eyes on her all night.
她动一动  我们就要知道
She doesn't move without us knowing about it.
轮流睡觉
Sleep in shifts.
如果你们要去别的地方  就找人一起去
If you go somewhere, take a buddy.
我们要和她们斗吗
We supposed to be fightin' them?
那边都是一群弱女子啊
'Cause that's the Lollipop Guild over there.
我说不好  红妈一直从外面弄东西进来
I don't know. Red's bringing all kinds of shit from the outside.
我听说她藏着一把泰瑟枪  以防万一
I hear she got a Taser hidden away for just in case.
你觉得她到底藏在哪里呢  在她下面吗
Where exactly you think she hiding it? In her coochie?
泰瑟枪肯定能塞得满满的
Taser would fit right in there.
红妈不是战士  而是搞计划的
Red's not a fighter. She's a schemer.
她要是有所行动
She makes a move,
我们要花一周时间才能想明白那是她干的
it'll take us a week to figure out it's her.
眼观六路  别和外人说话
Keep your eyes open. Don't talk to anyone that isn't us.
好了  听着
All right, listen up!
这栋大楼里的管道里全是水
This building's pipes are now compromised by water,
也就是说排水系统都不能用了
meaning there is absolutely no working plumbing whatsoever.
所以目前
So, for the time being,
你们要在便桶里上厕所
you're gonna answer nature's call in the honey bucket.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
走廊里还有四个
Four more just like it down the hallway.
你们跟门口的狱警说清楚
You check with the CO at the door,
去小便  然后把盖子盖上
you do your business, you put the lid back on.
满了一半时  最后上厕所的人就去外面倒了
Once it's halfway full, last person dumps it outside.
然后带回来
Brings it back.
如果要上大号呢
What if you gotta number two?
不行  憋住了  女士们
You don't. Keep it clenched, ladies.
别让大伙儿都受你的罪
Don't be the one to ruin it for everybody.
在某种方式上  这很棒
This is so great in a way, you know?
没有分离的宿舍  我们之间没有墙壁
No separate dorms, no walls between us.
我们只是女人
Like, we're all just women
一起经历着失去生活必需品
having the shared experience of deprivation.
就像绝食抗议一样  不过规模更大
Like, the hunger strike but bigger.
天啊  我们绝对要唱歌
Oh, my God, we should totally have a sing-along.
我讨厌如今的世界
I hate the world today
你对我很好
You're so good to me
我知道  但我没法改变
I know, but I can't change
想告诉你
Tried to tell you
但你看着我  好像我内心是个天使
But you look at me like maybe I'm an angel underneath
肉豆蔻  肉豆蔻
Nutmeg. Nutmeg.
-肉豆蔻  -是了
- Nutmeg! - Bing-fucking-go.
我们要吃多少才能嗨起来啊
How much we gotta eat to get gibbled?
我不知道  很多吧
I don't know. A lot.
-嘿  海利先生  -嘿
- Hey, Mr. Healy. - Hey.
-你好吗  -很好  你好吗
- How are you? - Good, how are you?
-不错  你有零食吗  -当然有
- Good, do you have any snacks? - Sure, sure.
来  在创伤咨询中心坐会儿吧
Come on, take a seat in the trauma counseling center.
你被风暴吓到了吗
So, is the storm scaring you?
让你觉得失去控制了
Making you feel out of control?
完全没有  我只是觉得很饿  想吃零食
Not at all. I just feel, like, hungry, like, for some snacks.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
这里有些零食
We got some snack food here.
-太棒了  谢谢  -不客气
- Oh, yes! Thank you. - You're welcome.
你要点水吗  保持水分很重要
Do you want some water? It's important to hydrate.
不要不要
No, no, no, no, no.
我要避免在桶里尿尿
There's this whole bucket situation that I'm trying to avoid.
我可以拿点回去给我邻居吗
Is it okay if I take a few of these for my neighbor?
因为她是个拉拉  我想分散她的注意力
'Cause she's a lesbian, and I just wanna, like, distract her.
是哪种拉拉
Which lesbian is that?
肚子很大  剪了头发的
With the fat stomach and the haircut.
布莱克[黑色]吗  她是最糟糕的
Black? She's, like, the worst one.
不  她是白人
No, she's white.
你不能在这里这样说  相信我
You know you can't say that shit around here. Trust me...
不不不
No. No, no, no.
你说的是大波  "布莱克"是她的姓
You're talking about Boo. "Black" is her last name.
你该离她远点
You should stay away from her.
你觉得我没法照顾自己吗
You think I can't handle myself?
我这样说吧
I will say this.
她纹了一些古怪的纹身
She's got some sick, like, tattoos, like her ink.
-你见过吗  -他们就是这样唬人的
- Have you seen it? - That's how they get you.
很酷  做很酷的事情
Being cool, doing cool things,
你还不知道  就被他们列入计划了
and before you know it, you're part of their agenda.
什么
What?
你该读读这本书  叫《男性末日》
You know, you should read this book. It's called The End of Men.
书里说的是很快
In it they talk about how, pretty soon,
男人就变得无关紧要
men are gonna become irrelevant.
女人受教育的程度更高
Now women are more educated,
能赚更多钱  掌管一切
they're gonna make more money and pretty much run everything.
真的吗
Really?
那谁来当总统呢
Well, then, who would, like, be the President?
就是啊
Exactly.
是女同性恋挑起了这事
It's the lesbians that started this whole thing.
她们用试管造婴儿
They're making babies out of a tube.
所以她们一直走来走去
That's why they're walking around
好像自己高人一等一样
all the time like they're better.
等着我们过时  她们就是这样
Waiting for us to go obsolete. That's what they're doing.
无意冒犯
No offense,
但是男人掌权  我从没有过什么好处
but, uh, men being in charge has never done me any good.
你是不是在吃免费饼干
Well, are you eating free cookies?
是啊
Yes.
瞎想之前你该想想这点
You should think about that before you get ideas.
别敲了
Yo, hold the fuck on.
你他妈是谁
Who the fuck is this?
我在道上听到了
I've been hearing some very troubling shit
关于你的闲话  我的朋友
on the street about you, my young friend.
拜托  维  很晚了
Come on, Vee, it's late.
擦  你这里有不少好东西啊
Damn, you got some nice shit up in here.
那是台新电视吗
Is that a new TV?
-如果是呢  -是吗
- What if it is? - Yeah?
我不记得给过你这么多钱
I don't remember handing you this kind of cash.
有个朋友帮我牵线搭桥
Got a friend that hooks me up.
一个朋友啊
A friend, huh?
因为我听说
'Cause what I hear...
你在自己偷偷做生意
you been going into business for yourself on the sly.
我的客户
My customers,
我的地盘
my corners.
维  我为你跑腿已经很久了  对吧
Yo, look, Vee, I've been running for you a long time, right?
你把我从领养院带回家  抚养我长大
You took me out of foster and raised me from a kid,
但我现在长大了
but I'm grown now.
我该自己去闯荡了
It's time for me to go out on my own.
那你是想在老娘的地盘
So, you wanna compete with me
跟我竞争吗  你个王八蛋
on my own fucking turf, you motherfucker?
拜托  维  你觉得我会那么耍你吗
Come on, now, Vee! Think I'm gonna play you hard like that?
对不起  好吗  我该告诉你
Look, I'm sorry, okay? I should've told you.
我想我是有点害怕
I guess I was kind of scared.
但是这样行吗  我给你提成
You know, but how's this? I'll give you a percentage.
不管你要什么
Whatever you want.
我不是想要耍你  维  我发誓
Look, I ain't trying to game you, Vee, I swear.
你觉得我会这样  我很受伤
It hurts me you even thinking I would.
别这样嘛
Come on, now.
好吧
Okay.
擦  好吧
Shit. Okay.
该死  我一定是心软了
Oh, God damn, I must be going soft,
因为你一直是我最喜欢的
'cause you always were my favorite.
我也感受到了
Yeah, I kind of got that feeling.
是啊  从你是个小男孩开始
Yeah, ever since you were a little boy.
但你现在是男人了
But you're a man now.
我想是的
Guess I am.
爱妈妈的男人
A man who loves his mama.
我也要转狱
You know... I'm being transferred, too...
所以至少我们会认识彼此
so at least we'll know each other.
我们不了解彼此
We don't know each other.
我知道  我只是说至少我们是从一个地方来的
I know, I just meant at least we'll both be from the same place.
我知道你为什么对此毫不在乎
And I can see why you wouldn't give a shit about that.
你要服刑多久
How much time do you have?
-六年  -擦
- Six years. - Fuck.
我看见你和你男朋友一起了
I saw you with your boyfriend.
看来他很爱你  对吧
Seems like he loves you a lot, huh?
他去死吧
Fuck him.
我最后会回家
I'm gonna come home finally,
我的孩子会上一年级  叫别的婊子"妈咪"
my baby'll be in the first grade calling some other puta "Mommy."
男人忍不住
Men can't help it.
他们很弱
They're weak.
好吧
Okay.
-喂  -什么
- Hey. - Hmm?
这个"计划"是怎么回事
How's this whole "Agenda" thing work?
我有很多呢  说具体点
I got a lot of those. Specify.
拉拉计划  接管世界
The gay agenda to take over the world?
好吧
Okay.
首先  小声点
First of all, keep your voice down.
这是绝密
This shit is top secret.
你要让所有男人都灭绝吗
Are you gonna let all the men die out?
当然不是  我们需要奴隶
Oh, fuck, no, we need slaves.
记帐  环卫
You know, bookkeeping, janitorial,
打杂之类的事
fetch and carry, that kind of shit.
那做爱呢
Yeah, what about for sex?
因为我知道我喜欢他们身上的体味
'Cause I know I like how they smell kind of funky
他们体型庞大  有老二什么的
and they're big and they have dicks and all that.
也许吧
Well, maybe...
但你搞完后  就得像扔垃圾一样扔掉他们
but when you're done, you gotta toss 'em away like trash.
这个的重点
I mean, the whole point of this
就是妹子们互相满足  掌握大权
is chicks digging each other and being in charge.
假设我想加入啊
Let's say I wanna join, right?
好吧  这样假设吧
Okay, let's say that.
我需要做违反上帝旨意的恶心事吗
Would I have to do anything disgusting against the word of God?
你懂的
You know?
我是说舔阴  你懂我的意思吧
I'm talking about eating pussy, if you catch my drift.
是的  我听到了
Yeah, I hear you.
我不撒谎  这是同性恋做爱的很大一部分
And that is a big part of it, I'm not gonna lie.
旦既然你有宗教信仰
But since you have these religious convictions,
我们可能让你免了
eh, we can probably give you an exemption.
我们不是不讲道理
I mean, we're not unreasonable.
真的吗  那就太棒了
Really? That'd be great.
当然  你还是得经历入会仪式
Of course, you're still gonna have to go through the initiation.
-我猜也是  -对
- Yeah, I figured. - Yeah.
做爱  结婚  杀人  卡普托  本尼特  奥尼尔
Fuck, marry, kill. Caputo, Bennett, O'Neill.
该死  这很容易  姑娘
Oh, shit, that's easy, girl.
我很想尝尝本尼特
I'd love to get me a piece of that Bennett.
即使他有假肢吗
Even with the stumpy stump?
姑娘  这样才有意思嘛
Girl, that's when the shit gets interesting.
那种男人觉得自己是在帮你个忙
It's the dudes like that think they doing you a favor.
-我会干卡普托  -是吗
- I'd fuck Caputo. - Mmm. Huh?
我喜欢胡子男
Yeah, I like me a mustache.
痒痒得舒服
Tickles in a good way.
而且他看起来总是很悲伤
And he always be looking so sad.
他肯定格外努力
Bet he work extra hard.
是啊
Yep.
我想到一个
Yo, I got one.
做爱  结婚  杀人  赫克特堡一家
Fuck, marry, kill... the Huxtables.
我们现在有点忙
You know, we're kind of busy right now.
你们都不想跟我说话吗
Y'all ain't even gonna talk to me?
她说要让我跟以前一样售货
She said she'd move me back to sales.
我什么都没做
I didn't even do nothin'.
我们很忙
We're busy.
这里好多人
There's too many people in here.
味道不怎么好闻
It's making the air feel weird.
大部分是屁味
Just mostly farts.
不  我简直没法呼吸
No, it's like I can't breathe.
我没法呼吸
I can't breathe.
我的宝宝没法呼吸  开灯
My baby can't breathe. Turn on the lights.
没光  会没事的
There's no lights. It's gonna be okay.
我得离开这里  我得离开这里
I gotta get out of here. I gotta get out of here.
我没法呼吸  我没法呼吸
I can't breathe. I can't breathe!
会没事的
It's okay.
你接电话了  我猜11是我的幸运数字
You picked up. I guess 11 is my lucky number.
你为什么打电话来
Why are you calling?
因为这里漆黑一片  人们在桶里尿尿
Because it's pitch black and people are pissing in buckets,
我说的"人们"  也包括我
and when I say "People," I'm also talking about me.
电动大门打不开
The electric gate won't open,
洗衣房里简直水流成河
there's a river running through the fucking laundry.
道路被冲毁了  你指望我现在做什么
The roads are washed out. What do you expect me to do right now?
-我这是听到了轻爵士乐吗  -是的  乔
- Do I hear light jazz? - Yes, you do, Joe,
因为我在上西区参加鸡尾酒晚会
because I am at a cocktail party on the Upper West Side,
和纽约巨头们喝萨塞拉克鸡尾酒
drinking Sazeracs with the New York Giants.
你想听的就是这个吗
Is that what you wanted to hear?
我很抱歉  但你得自己挺过来
I am sorry, but you're gonna have to ride this shit out.
我们早上再谈
We will talk about it in the morning.
我保证我们肯定会谈的
Oh, I guarantee we're gonna talk about it.
我们要谈谈你管理不善的傻逼借口
We are gonna talk about how your shitty excuse for management
最后一次害了老子
has fucked me for the last fucking time.
你觉得自己能做得更好吗
You think you could do a better job?
因为如果我们看看
'Cause if we look at the evidence from,
最近几周的证据
say, the last few weeks...
我是说  也许
I'm saying that maybe
一个本是典狱长的秘书  后来飞黄腾达的人
someone who came up a different path from Warden's secretary,
一个溜须拍马  做颈部按摩的人
who kissed ass and gave neck massages,
也许会记得给备用发电机订柴油
might've remembered to order diesel for the backup genny.
好吧
Okay.
那我回去后
So, we will be discussing
我们会谈论你在惩教署的职业前景
the future of your career at the DOC when I get back,
但现在  我需要你撑住了
but for now, I need you to suck it the fuck up,
搞定这事  别哭了
ride this out, stop crying,
还有别给我打电话了
and stop calling me.
喂
Hello?
离无声拍卖就五分钟了
Five minutes left for the silent auction!
想象一个快乐的地方  一个好地方
Think of a happy place. Someplace nice,
比如说美丽的海滩  或者山  或者
like a beautiful beach, or like a mountain, or...
她喜欢海滩或者山吗
Does she like beaches or mountains or...
-我不  -她喜欢莫里斯公园的漫画书店
- I don't... - She likes the comic book store on Morris Park.
好吧  漫画  到处都是漫画
Okay, yeah, so comics. There's comics everywhere.
一大片漫画的海洋  范围广阔
Just a sea of comics as far as your eye can see.
一大堆漫画书来抚慰你
A cocoon of comic books just comforting you.
站起来  迪亚茨
On your feet, Diaz.
拜托  她身体不舒服
Hey, come on, man, she's not doing well.
我说了起来
I said, get up!
你非得现在这么混蛋吗
Do you really have to be a dick right now?
做跳跃运动  20个  开始
Jumping jacks. 20. Go.
我做不到
I can't.
-你在违抗警卫吗  -照做
- You defying an officer? - Do it.
一  二  二  三
One, two, two, three...
你要做点什么吗
You gonna do something?
我去叫卡普托
I'm gonna get Caputo.
-大声点  -六  七  八  九
- Out loud. - ... six, seven, eight, nine...
继续呼吸  数数呼吸
Keep breathin'. Count your breaths.
好的
Yeah, okay.
有人来了
Incoming.
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
这是花生酱和果酱三明治  我觉得我能搞定
It's PB and J. I feel like I got this.
你放的果冻离边缘太近了
You're putting the jelly too close to the edges.
你得平均放  不然就会漏出来
You got to even it out, or it leaks.
这怎么回事啊
Is this happening?
-你想要什么  -没什么
- What do you want? - Nothing.
基本上不算件事
Practically nothing.
你有刀笼的钥匙吗
You've got the keys to the knife cage?
把钥匙丢在地上  一会儿再来找
Just drop them on the ground, find them again later.
这是个很容易的错误
It's an easy mistake.
是为了自卫
It's for self-defense.
一把刀不见了
And when a knife comes up missing,
你觉得我会怎么样
what do you think's gonna happen to me?
她弄丢了钥匙  我们别重罚她
"Oh, she lost the keys, so let's go easy on her ass."
她会杀了我的  曼多萨
She's going to kill me, Mendoza.
当着整个监狱的人的面吗
What, in front of the whole prison?
天啊  你真是多疑死了
Man, you are paranoid as shit.
好吧  忘了刀吧  给我点尖东西
Fine, forget the knife. Just give me something sharp.
奶酪刨
The cheese grater.
她真是烦死我了
你以前是个人物  知道吗  红妈
You used to be something, you know that, Red?
现在你疯了  真可悲
Now you lost your damn mind. And it's sad.
她没必要跟你斗  她已经赢了
She don't need to fight you, 'cause she already won.
罗莎小姐
Miss Rosa?
天啊  好了  喂
Oh, jeez. All right. Hey, hey.
我还没死呢
I'm not dead yet.
如果你担心的是这事
If that's what's itching you.
不不  我还以为
No. No, I thought...
我知道看起来不大好
I mean, I know it's not looking so good.
最糟糕的部分不是慢慢死去
It's not the dying that's the bad part.
而是得在这里死
It's that I gotta do it here, you know?
我最后看到的  是你们这些混蛋
The last thing I'm gonna see... is you assholes.
你刚有点吓到我了
You scared me for a minute there.
她生下来时怎么办
What's gonna happen when she's born?
他们会让你妈妈的家人带走她
Well, they'll let your mom's family take her.
我有空能去看她
I can go see her sometimes.
然后呢
And then what?
你要告诉她  你是她爸爸吗
You gonna tell her you're her daddy?
但她得闭嘴
But she needs to keep her mouth shut
因为大家都以为她爸爸是另一个人
because everybody thinks that she has a different daddy?
那个爸爸在监狱里  因为他干了妈妈
And that daddy's in jail because he put his dick in Mommy...
但是无所谓吗
but be cool?
我就不该给你那块口香糖  对吧
I should never have given you that gum... should I?
你做了很多蠢事
You did a lot of stupid things.
我也是  我俩都是
And so did I. It was both of us.
但那不重要了
But it doesn't matter anymore.
我们得做对孩子最好的事
We have to do what's best for the kid.
那是什么
Which is what?
坦白
Confess.
-然后蹲监狱吗  -是啊
- And go to prison? - Yeah.
蹲监狱  服刑
Go to prison. Do your time.
我会告诉他我爱你
I'll tell him I love you.
我们几年后都会出狱  告别这个地方
We'll both get out in a few years, we're done with this place,
我们是一家人
we're a family.
或者
Or...
走开不管
walk away.
我不会怪的你
I won't blame you.
重新开始
Get a fresh start.
好像这事没发生过一样
It's like this never happened.
这一切都怪在门德斯头上
This whole mess is on Mendez.
我的小孩长大后不会觉得困惑
My baby won't grow up confused.
你觉得我是那种会离开孩子的人吗
You think I'm the kind of man that walks away from my kid?
笨蛋
Dummy.
你现在有机会及时回头
You got a chance right now to go back in time.
如果有人给我这种机会
If someone gave that to me,
我肯定会考虑的
I would sure as hell be thinking about it.
你有没有想过我们为啥一直都穿衣服
Do you ever think about why we wear clothes all the time?
真正地思考
Like, really think about it?
我感觉被困在了脸里
I feel trapped inside my face.
铺位那边有三英寸积水
We got 3 inches of water in the bunks.
现在水从图书馆门下流进来了
And now the water's coming in under the library door.
那书怎么办
Yo, what about the books?
-怎么了  -会被毁坏的
- What about 'em? - They'll get ruined.
那可值钱了
Yo, that shit's worth money.
你知道管理层会多生气吗
You know how pissed they'd be upstairs?
去吧  把书放在高层架子上
Go on. Get 'em up on a high shelf.
我几分钟后去找你
I'll check on you in a few.
带个人去
And... and take a buddy.
你  你了解图书馆  跟她一起去
You. Yeah, you know the library. Go with her.
先搬贵重的书
And pull the expensive stuff first.
起身
Roll up.
压力进入了脊椎
Stress goes right to the spine.
-修女怎么样  -还在医务室
- How's Sister? - Still in medical.
大概还是别人给她喂东西
Being force-fed, presumably.
-她让我惭愧  -不是她
- She makes me ashamed of myself. - It is not her.
又是菲格
It's Fig again.
谁会那样对一个老女人呢
Who does that to an old lady?
不管怎么样  他们总是会赢
They always win one way or another.
如果他们赢不了  就把我们转狱
And if they can't, they just transfer us away.
我好害怕
I'm so scared.
飞机上好冷
It's so cold on the plane,
男人们就盯着你看
and the men, they just stare.
然后你下了飞机  到了一个
Then you get off and you're in this place
你谁也不认识的地方
where you don't know anyone.
我在奥尔德森监狱过了五个月
I spent five months at Alderson.
那里跟这里一样吗
Was it like here?
那里棒极了
It was awesome.
虽然是被剥夺了人身自由
I mean, as far as being deprived of your personal freedom
和公民自由
and civil liberties goes.
那边有工艺商品店和排球队
They had a crafts shop and a volleyball team.
我睡的是玛莎・斯图尔特老床铺
I had Martha Stewart's old bunk.
这地方烂透了
This place is bullshit.
你比我想象中的更有勇气
You got more balls than I thought.
现在谁可悲了
Who's pathetic now?
天啊
Oh, God!
来吧  来吧
Go ahead. Go ahead.
这地方让我变坏了
This place is getting to me.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
你刚想用保鲜膜勒死我
You just tried to strangle me with plastic wrap
好让自己能在监狱里卖睫毛膏
so that you can sell mascara in jail.
这真蠢
This is stupid.
你想要什么都拿走吧  我还在乎什么
Take what you want. What do I care?
我想证明什么呢
What am I trying to prove?
我俩井水不犯河水  好吗
You keep yours, I'll keep mine, all right?
我们已经在这里闹得太厉害了
We've got enough fucking hell in here already.
休战
Truce.
你就不能在干点儿的地方杀我吗
You couldn't try to kill me someplace drier?
天啊
Oh, God.
你知道我现在想要什么吗
Oh, you know what I want right now?
什么
What?
天啊  炸弹冰棍
Oh, God, a Bomb Pop.
老娘要一根冰棍
I need a fucking popsicle.
红色白色蓝色  很爱国
Red, white, and blue. Very patriotic.
你现在觉得很爱国吗
You feeling patriotic now?
拜托  记得我教给你的
Come on, now, remember what I taught you.
对自己的女人要像对女王一样
Always treat your lady like a queen.
你去帮我买
You go get it for me,
我也许会让你再来一次最后那花式
I might let you do that last thing again.
-擦  -去吧
- Fuck. - Go on, now.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thank you, baby.
你好啊  RJ
What's up, RJ?
我什么也没做
I ain't done nothin', man.
我只是要去买冰淇淋  就这样
I'm just going to get ice cream. That's it.
-接住了  -搞毛啊
- Catch. - What the fuck?
麦克马伦公园的台阶上有个潜逃者
I got a runner on the steps at McMullen Park.
非裔美国人  男性  20出头
African-American male, early 20's,
持有武器  有侵略性
armed and aggressive.
请求支援
Request backup.
别  求你别这样做
Oh, no. Please don't do this, man.
拜托了  警官  不要...
Please, Officer, don't...
你是要来帮忙  还是要站在那里吓坏我
You gonna help or just stand there creepin' me out?
滚你的
Fuck you.
维会对我做什么
So, what's Vee gonna do to me?
她不会对你做什么的
She ain't gonna do nothin' to you.
好吧
Right.
她把我赶走了
She threw me out.
这就是你想要的  对吧
That's what you wanted, ain't it?
你赢了
You win.
我这辈子唯一关心我的人
The only person that ever looked out for me in my entire life,
你让她不理我了
you got her back to turn.
唯一的吗
The only person?
滚你的
Well, fuck you.
你毁了一切
You ruined everything.
你就不能安心当我朋友
You... you couldn't just be my friend.
你非得搞砸一切
You gotta... you gotta go turn it wrong.
你得...想脱我的衣服
You gotta... Wanna take off my clothes...
天啊  我什么时候跟你提过那种事
Oh, God, when did I ever say a word to you about...
你说了  你说了很多话
You said... you said plenty of words.
你就不能让我拥有一件东西
You couldn't let me have one damn thing to myself.
她不是个好人  美味姐
She's not a good person, Taystee.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你毁了我的生活
You fucked up my life.
我受够了
I'm done.
你现在就要这样走了吗
You just gonna walk away now, too?
搞什么...
What the...
天啊  天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
对不起  珀比
I'm sorry, P.
-对不起  -我知道
- I'm sorry. - I know.
-对不起  -我知道  我知道
- I'm sorry. - I know. I know.
菲茨核心
你想解释一下吗
You want to explain?